MIRAJ ARYAL

0411381165 | mirajaryal@gmail.com

Professional Summary

A Full Stack Developer with knowledge in different front end and back end languages, responsive frameworks, databases, and best code practices. My objective is simply to be the best developer that I can be and to contribute to the technology industry. I am dedicated to perfecting my craft by self-learning and from experienced developers, remaining humble, and continuously making strides to learn all that I can about development. I have over 2 years of experience in developing websites using PHP/MYSQL, CMS-based/eCommerce websites using Advanced WordPress, integrating RESTful APIs and Payment Gateways. Skilled in frontend technologies such as HTML, CSS, Vanilla JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, SCSS. I can effectively work as a team member or individually.

Technical Skills

Web Technologies: PHP/MySQL, Advanced WordPress, HTML/CSS, SCSS, Vanilla JS, React JS,

AJAX, jQuery, Bootstrap, Google Analytics, Search Console, Tag Manager, EDM (Mailchimp).

Familiar with: Angular JS 1.x, Node.js, Python

Frameworks: Codelgniter, Laravel, Yii2 **Database:** MySQL, MongoDB (Basics)

Tools: VSCode, Bracket, Atlassian Tools Suite (Jira, Confluence), VM Virtual Box, Asana, Slack

Platforms: Windows, Mac

Version Control: GitHub, Bitbucket

Professional Experience

Full-Stack Developer

Sept 2020 - Feb 2021

Pictura Creative, North Sydney, NSW

- Responsible for the development of project from start to finish.
- Develop the websites using **Advanced WordPress** for different service-based clients like Home Builders, Hotel, Online Shopping, Trade Services, etc.
- Write effective codes to match as close as possible to the design.
- Write **reusable code components** using Advanced Custom Field to build custom CMS in order to increase flexibility and avoid use of page builders.
- Test websites to ensure responsiveness and efficiency, implement latest CSS techniques like **flexbox** and **grid** to achieve complex **responsive** layouts.
- Redesigned and dramatically simplified an overly complex websites, while preserving all functionality.

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

- Integrate payment gateways like Stripe, PayPal, AfterPay to ecommerce websites.
- Developed the website that is SEO ready, has full control over H tags without affecting the design.
- Implement Avanser, Google Analytics, Google Search Console and Google Tag Manager.
- Implement 301 **redirection** and 404 page so that google does not penalise the website which affects the ranking of the website.
- Achieved a Lighthouse score of 70+ on frontend.
- Troubleshoot, debug and upgrade websites to ensure it's running in latest version of web technologies.
- Create **security** and data protection settings.
- Build features and applications with a mobile responsive design.
- Cross Browser testing using VM Virtual Box to ensure the website functions correctly over all or most of the browsers.
- Write **technical documentation** and store it in internal knowledge base wiki **Confluence**.
- Deliver clean and functional code within a timely manner.
- Perform **domain registration**, **cPanel** configuration, SSL certification, etc to ensure website registration and **hosting** task is completed and recorded in WHMCS.

Web Developer (Contract Job)

Jan 2020 – Mar 2020

Spark Interact, Marrickville, NSW

- Joined to support the overseas dev team working on a PHP application for a hospital in Vietnam.
- Served as a bridge between the overseas dev team and the Production Manager, cross-check the codes implemented by the developers; address and fix the issues if any, implement any changes or ideas as required.
- Troubleshoot any errors in the websites of existing client.
- Write a report on functionality, interactivity and responsiveness of websites and report it to the Production Manager.

Web Developer Jun 2017 - Nov 2019

Everest View Travel & Tours, Rockdale, NSW

- Developed websites and web apps for ticket management system, special request page, travel forum, etc. using PHP/MySQL.
- Use of mailer libraries like **PHPMailer**, Swiftmailer for powerful component-based mailing for PHP based websites.
- Worked on **Cross-Browser Compatibility** and tested each & every web application on popular web browsers such as Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, Opera and Chrome.
- Used Media Queries to deal with different CSS related issues on different devices.
- Configured web servers and web host; served as the server administrator.
- Implemented business ideas from owner into web application, creating an effective bridge between customer and the business.
 - For example: Created manage booking website where customers can request for flight change, seat allocation, flight cancellation, special meal request or special need request to the travel agency online through the <u>manage booking website</u>.
- Managed plugins and themes for the main website developed using WordPress CMS.

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

PHP Developer Feb 2014 - Mar 2015

Imagine Web Solution Pvt Ltd, Nepal

- Wrote Procedural and OOP PHP codes to develop a website.
- Developed different websites using MVC framework, Codelgniter mostly.
- Experience integrating with backend RESTFUL APIs.
- SVN for project version control.
- Developed several websites for Education, Medical, E-commerce sector.
- Onsite Communication with clients and handle modification quickly.

Education

Master of Technology (Software Engineering) Federation University, Australia Bachelor of Computer Science & Engineering ANNA University, India

Personal Skills

- **Fast Learner**: Ability to grasp new technology in short time and implement it. Recently started working on Advanced WordPress and solely completed development of 3 major projects.
- **Knowledge, Creativity and Problem Solving**: Good understanding of programming concept which helps in problem-solving and be creative with logics to achieve expected output.
- **Dedication**: I tend to give my all when I'm doing a project. I enjoy my work and take pride in it. I work off hours to learn and experiment new things that would help me achieve better output.
- **Passion for Knowledge**: I'm very excited to learn and grasp new technologies and update my skills.
- **Punctual**: I'm always on time unless affected by any external factor.

Achievements/Awards

- Invited to the exclusive Golden Key International Honour Society for outstanding academic achievement.
- Commendation letter from university for outstanding academic performance in Semester 2

Hobbies

- Art & Photography: Facebook Page
- Music: YouTube Channel
- Cooking: Chef @Bondi Icebergs Group, La Rosa The Strand, Keg & Brew Hotel

References

Available upon request.